A Guide to the Kathryn H. Stone Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10555-c
Kathryn H. Stone Papers 1916-1995
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10555-c
ca. 225 items
Suzanne Stone
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Ms. Suzanne Stone of Narberth, Pennsylvania through Ms. Jane Wilhelm of Reston, Virginia, on July 26, 1995.
Scope and Content
There are ca. 225 items, 1916 (1941-1985) 1995, of Kathryn H. Stone consisting of correspondence, papers, and printed material pertaining to Stone and her political career, 1932-1995. Material on Burgundy Farm Country Day School consists of organizational papers, by-laws, history, and brochures, 1946-1971; and,
Burgundy Voice
s and papers concerning campus renewal and the campaign to raise funds, 1992-1995. Topics discussed in the correspondence include: the Governor's Commission on the Status of Women in Virginia(January 8, 1968); Stone's state papers and the George Mason Library(May 29, 1969); the National Civil Service League papers and the University of Wyoming Archive of Contemporary History(September 6, 1970); Arlington School Integration 1959-1984 (June 11, 1984); Acharya Kakasaheb Kalelkar(November 27 and December 9, 1985); the Coalition to Improve Management in State and Local Government(July 28, 1986); Stone's contribution to the Virginiana and archival collections of the Arlington County Public Library(January 23, 1985); and, personal news of family and friends, 1981-1995. Among the correspondence of the Stone children and grandchildren are letters of Abel L. Lenz and a newspaper article (post 1986) on Joanna Stone. The League of Women Voters papers contain material on woman suffrage, Anna Lord Strauss, Belle Sherwin(October 11, 1986 letter), and, the 70th anniversary of the LWV; and, also include a certificate of merit presented to Stone in 1986, a list of former board members (August 1986), and, two pamphlets. Newspaper articles, 1941-1995, pertain to Stone and her political career and include her obituaries. There are two photographs of Kathryn Haeseler (Meyers) Stone on a Camera Club Hike in 1932. Political papers include a press release on the Joint Committee on the Organization of Congress(June 11, 1945); campaign material for 1953, 1961, and 1963; statements concerning the consideration of Stone for the position of Undersecretary of Health, Education and Welfare (January 3 & 6, 1961); "Testimony of Mrs. Kathryn H. Stone...before the State Mental Hygiene and Hospital Board, Richmond, Virginia --March 9, 1961"; and, a statement pertaining to a bill to provide a minimum wage for Virginia (February 5, 1964). Material on women issues include Stone's article, "Women as Citizens," May 1947, and miscellaneous newspaper articles; material on youth issues include a broadside on "The League of Women Voters of Arlington, VA....An Adequate Juvenile Care Program...March 14, 1953, and other papers.
Container List
- Anecdotes and Quotes used for Opening Remarks of Speeches
- Biographical Sketches of Kathryn H. Stone, 1959-1977
- Burgundy Farm Country Day School, 1946-1971, n.d.
- Burgundy Farm Country Day School, 1992-1995
- Correspondence of Kathryn H. and Harold A. Stone, 1968-1995
- Correspondence of the Stone children and grandchildren, 1993
- Genealogy of the Alspach, Bittle, Haeseler, Heisey, and Pfautz families, 1916 (1943-1983)
- League of Women Voters, 1970-1990
- Newspaper Articles chiefly re Kathryn H. Stone and political issues, 1941-1995
- Photographs of Kathryn H. Stone, 1932
- Political Papers re Kathryn H. Stone, 1945-1964
- Women and Youth Issues, 1947-1981